<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>My blog about myself as an autist and my experiences with autism. Information and explanation for people without autism, a view of the world from someone with autism.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <link>https://myautisticself.nl/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://myautisticself.nl/feed_en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 09:19:53 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 09:19:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator><item>
        <title>Meltdown - Old vs New behavior</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/a-blue-brain-with-lightning-bolts.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mind Melting Down&quot; class=&quot;ui image floated right&quot; /&gt; My thoughts are running through my head and through each other. My head is full and I notice I’m scared. My body gives all the classical signals for this; my heart beats much faster, my eyes wander over everything without seeing much, my breathing is much faster than normal. For me the worst thing is that I lose my self-control, my grip on my reactions and the mask with which I filter my statements normally.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In short, this is my so-called meltdown. A meltdown is not something that only children with autism have, even adult autistic people run into it from time to time. And for every autistic person a meltdown is different. There are certainly similarities between meltdowns and they are all extremely miserable.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-a-meltdown-for-me&quot;&gt;What’s a meltdown for me?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like everything on this blog, I write this from my own experience, my view of the world. Like I wrote, a meltdown is different for everyone. My meltdowns are characterized by the loss of my social mask and the inability to interact socially. It often expresses itself in anger and sadness. Answers to questions are short and with an...
        <br />
        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/01/meltdown-old-vs-new-behavior.html
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 12:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/01/meltdown-old-vs-new-behavior.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/01/meltdown-old-vs-new-behavior.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>meltdown</category><category>persoonlijk</category><category>sociaal-gedrag</category></item><item>
        <title>36 questions for me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Something different today. On different blogs you will come across them, the lists of questions generally asked to people to get to know each other better. So there are 36 of them and I try to answer them all below. If you have any more questions about this question and answer session, please let me know via for example &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WesterinkDavid&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/myautisticself/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; :smile:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But now, without further delay, the questions and answers:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;are-you-an-introvert-or-an-extrovert&quot;&gt;Are you an introvert or an extrovert?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have called myself an introvert for years. Nowadays I’m not so sure. I think I fall somewhere between the two extremes. Although I am very fond of my own space and certainly need it to recharge, I also enjoy talking to people and going out with friends. Unfortunately I don’t do the latter enough, largely for financial reasons.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;suppose-you-only-have-a-year-to-live-what-would-you-do&quot;&gt;Suppose you only have a year to live, what would you do?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Say goodbye to friends and family. Put things in order. Show my children how to deal with the impending death. And maybe some less beautiful things I’d better not make public.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;what-did-you-want-to-be-as-a-child&quot;&gt;What did you want to be as a child?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Policeman. That seemed like a...
        <br />
        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/01/36-inquiries.html
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 10:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/01/36-inquiries.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/01/36-inquiries.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>persoonlijk</category></item><item>
        <title>Autism as a cloud</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;A spectrum (also called gradient) - (plural: spectra or spectrums) is a range of consecutive colours or sounds or other varieties. This term is often used in physics. &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spectrum&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/ads-cloud-head.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/assets/resized/80/ads-cloud-head.jpg 80w,/assets/resized/20/ads-cloud-head.jpg 20w,/assets/resized/300/ads-cloud-head.jpg 300w, /assets/img/ads-cloud-head.jpg 395w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;progressive replace ui image floated medium right&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/resized/20/ads-cloud-head.jpg&quot; class=&quot;preview ui image floated medium right&quot; alt=&quot;Autism als een wolk&quot; title=&quot;Autism als een wolk&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When we talk about ASD one of the first things we do is pronounce the abbreviation completely; Autism Spectrum Disorder. About the last word, disorder, &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/07/disorder-condition-disease.html&quot;&gt;I’ve already written&lt;/a&gt;. Today I’d like to discuss the second word, spectrum.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As the definition indicates, a spectrum is a range of successive diversities. In my opinion, this is an incorrect representation of autism. It leads to different problems when thinking about autism. It leads to the labeling of forms of autism, the thinking that there are “not bad” and “heavy” forms of autism, that you can place someone on a straight line and so on by means of some outward displays. I think it is not as easy as that. People with autism are very different, but classifying them in a straight line doesn’t...
        <br />
        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/01/autism-as-a-cloud.html
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 09:48:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/01/autism-as-a-cloud.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/01/autism-as-a-cloud.html</guid><category>autisme</category></item><item>
        <title>Thinking in terms of solutions, not problems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/creatief-denken.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/assets/resized/80/creatief-denken.jpg 80w,/assets/resized/20/creatief-denken.jpg 20w, /assets/img/creatief-denken.jpg 300w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;progressive replace ui image floated medium right&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/resized/20/creatief-denken.jpg&quot; class=&quot;preview ui image floated medium right&quot; alt=&quot;Thinking in terms of solutions&quot; title=&quot;Thinking in terms of solutions&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A few years ago a manager said to me: “We need to start thinking more in terms of solutions within this company”. This statement stayed with me when I started to rebuild myself. Another statement I once heard (I don’t know exactly when, it’s been a long time) is: “Problems are problems, because they have a solution. If a problem has no solution, it is not a problem but a fact”. From these two statements I have reasoned further for myself. If a problem has no solution, it is a fact. Ergo; if a fact has a solution, it is a problem. Facts are by definition not “solvable”, they can change, but (mostly) you can’t change that much yourself.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It may sound like I’m trying to put my problems aside with this, but that’s not quite what I mean by that. If you “solve” a problem in your life as far as you can, but it’s still there (assuming it has decreased in size or...
        <br />
        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/01/thinking-in-terms-of-solutions-not-problems.html
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 12:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/01/thinking-in-terms-of-solutions-not-problems.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/01/thinking-in-terms-of-solutions-not-problems.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>filosofie</category><category>gedachtes</category><category>positief</category><category>depressie</category></item><item>
        <title>Happy Holidays and a Happy New Year!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/12/end-of-the-year.html&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I already looked back at 2019. Today I would simply like to wish you all Happy Holidays and a Happy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading my blogs and the feedback I’m receiving through Facebook/Twitter and &lt;abbr title=&quot;In Real Life&quot;&gt;IRL&lt;/abbr&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/feestdagen-nieuwjaar.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/assets/resized/80/feestdagen-nieuwjaar.jpg 80w,/assets/resized/20/feestdagen-nieuwjaar.jpg 20w,/assets/resized/300/feestdagen-nieuwjaar.jpg 300w,/assets/resized/250/feestdagen-nieuwjaar.jpg 250w,/assets/resized/500/feestdagen-nieuwjaar.jpg 500w, /assets/img/feestdagen-nieuwjaar.jpg 1280w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;progressive replace &quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/resized/20/feestdagen-nieuwjaar.jpg&quot; class=&quot;preview &quot; alt=&quot;Happy Holidays and a Happy New Year!&quot; title=&quot;Happy Holidays and a Happy New Year!&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


        <br />
        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2019/12/happy-holidays-and-a-happy-new-year.html
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 11:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/12/happy-holidays-and-a-happy-new-year.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/12/happy-holidays-and-a-happy-new-year.html</guid><category>feestdagen</category><category>2019</category></item><item>
        <title>End of the year</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/einde-vh-jaar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;End of the year&quot; class=&quot;floated right ui image large&quot; /&gt; It’s the end of the year. 2019 was a year for me in which a lot has happened. It is the year in which I started this blog and in which I developed myself personally. Christmas is just around the corner and in all sorts of places on the internet people round off their year and look back.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;blogging-about-autism&quot;&gt;Blogging about autism&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;This year I started with this blog. My goal was not fixed when I started this blog; I wanted to write about autism and how I experience the world around me. Since I started with this blog, I have found out more and more that I want to work towards the acceptance of autism and neurodiversity. Writing my blog gives me a lot; I’m learning more and more about myself and my autistic side, I’ve met people on Twitter and noticed that there are people who appreciate my blogs. It is certainly something I will continue to do in the new year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Although I’ve often started things in the past and had trouble finishing them (so many projects I started with an idea, but ended up...
        <br />
        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2019/12/end-of-the-year.html
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 11:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/12/end-of-the-year.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/12/end-of-the-year.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>2019</category><category>review</category><category>podcasts</category></item><item>
        <title>Welcome to the team little guy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/autism-little-elephant.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Little autistic elephant&quot; class=&quot;floated right ui image rounded&quot; /&gt; You turned 6 this year. Ever since you were two, your mother has noticed differences between you and your sister. And yesterday you were diagnosed with autism. And now I can officially welcome you to the neurodiverse world. Your mother and I have known for ages that you are on the spectrum, your behavior and your difficulties are very recognizable to me. Also my guidance and the help at your mother’s home, who has a lot of experience with autism, found that you were very clearly on the spectrum.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And now I welcome you to the “club”, the “tribe” or the team. And I’m very happy that we now have the diagnosis officially. This means that in the future you can get the help you need. It means that money will be available to help you. It also confirms what we have known for years; you really look like your father.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;fighting-for-acceptance&quot;&gt;Fighting for acceptance&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;With my blog I fight for acceptance of neurodiversity. Now not only for myself and others, but also for you. I wish you a world that doesn’t look down on you. That people see...
        <br />
        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2019/12/welcome-to-the-team-little-guy.html
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 12:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/12/welcome-to-the-team-little-guy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/12/welcome-to-the-team-little-guy.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>persoonlijk</category><category>neurodiversiteit</category><category>kinderen</category><category>persoonlijk</category></item><item>
        <title>What is Neurodiversity?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/neurodiversity.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hello Friend!&quot; class=&quot;ui floated right image rounded&quot; /&gt; When I started looking for Twitterers to follow about autism, I soon came across @NeuroRebel. She has been (among other things) a great inspiration to start this blog. She is someone who fights for acceptance of autism and similar characteristics. The Twitter title she uses is “Neurodivergent Rebel” and that is freely translated “Neurodiverse Rebel” and soon made me look at the term neurodiversity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What is neurodiversity anyway? And why is it used? It’s a term first used in the late 1990s by sociologist Judy Singer and journalist Harvey Blume. They are talking about natural variations in the human brain on different fronts such as sociability, learning, attention, mood and other mental functions in a non pathological way. Pathology is disease theory, or the study of diseases. By describing autism in a non-pathological way, we try to deviate from the view that autism is a disease. Rather, it is a social handicap in a non-autistic world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;neurodiversity-contains-more-than-just-autism&quot;&gt;Neurodiversity contains more than just autism&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Although the term was used in the late 1990s as an alternative way of looking at autism, it was later adopted to encompass more than just autism....
        <br />
        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2019/11/what-is-neurodiversity.html
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 14:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/11/what-is-neurodiversity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/11/what-is-neurodiversity.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>neurodiversiteit</category><category>persoonlijk</category><category>dit-is-autisme</category></item><item>
        <title>Asperger is also just autism</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Depositphotos_19699563_s-2015.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Asperger is also just autism&quot; class=&quot;ui small image right floated&quot; /&gt; There are people who don’t think Asperger’s syndrome is autistic. These people think that Asperger is so far removed from classical autism that it does not even fall into the same spectrum. This is often because they do not want to be associated with autism. The reasons for this range from refusing to accept that they are autistic to the negativity that accompanies autism.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let me be clear; Asperger falls within the autism spectrum. That it is not the same as classical autism is also very clear. But it is still autism. In fact, in the DSM 5 it is the case that Asperger’s syndrome is no longer mentioned. It falls under the heading of autism. Tony Attwood wrote the following about this &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/08/guide-asperger-syndrome-review.html#addition---the-dsm-5&quot;&gt;change&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The deletion of the term &quot;Asperger's syndrome&quot; will have a negative impact on the sense of identity of adults who have benefited from the term, have set up peer groups and have access to literature and support groups on the Internet based on common characteristics and experiences. Clinical experience shows that most adults with Asperger's syndrome and their family members want...
        <br />
        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2019/11/asperger-is-also-just-autism.html
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 10:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/11/asperger-is-also-just-autism.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/11/asperger-is-also-just-autism.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>asperger</category><category>honger-naar-informatie</category></item><item>
        <title>Autumn days, relaxation days</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/CrispAutumnDay.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/assets/resized/80/CrispAutumnDay.jpg 80w,/assets/resized/20/CrispAutumnDay.jpg 20w,/assets/resized/300/CrispAutumnDay.jpg 300w,/assets/resized/250/CrispAutumnDay.jpg 250w, /assets/img/CrispAutumnDay.jpg 653w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;progressive replace ui image floated medium right&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/resized/20/CrispAutumnDay.jpg&quot; class=&quot;preview ui image floated medium right&quot; alt=&quot;Wonderful autumn&quot; title=&quot;Wonderful autumn&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s wonderful, the fall. The days become shorter, the nights longer, the weather colder and the people less often on the street. Most of them stay at home in front of the tube, or if they have a fireplace. I do enjoy it. The year is coming to an end. It’s getting colder and colder, the winter is coming.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Winter is my favourite season. I can handle the cold, but the heat of the summer is a big challenge for me. So I like the winter a lot more. All the “nasty” things of the winter are not that bad either; the cold, the slippery, the short days. For me these are not really problems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;short-days-long-nights&quot;&gt;Short days, long nights&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;I know for myself that I’m a nocturnal animal. I can stay awake at night without too many problems. On the other hand, I prefer to sleep the days. If I “fall back” to my natural rhythm, it is also much more likely that I live the nights and...
        <br />
        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2019/11/autumn-days-relaxation-days.html
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 10:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/11/autumn-days-relaxation-days.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/11/autumn-days-relaxation-days.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>herfst</category><category>asperger</category></item></channel>
</rss>
