<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>My blog about myself as an autist and my experiences with autism. Information and explanation for people without autism, a view of the world from someone with autism.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <link>https://myautisticself.nl/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://myautisticself.nl/feed_en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 13:52:32 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 13:52:32 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator><item>
        <title>I am an autist vs I have autism</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/identityfirst.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;/assets/resized/80/identityfirst.jpg 80w,/assets/resized/20/identityfirst.jpg 20w,/assets/resized/300/identityfirst.jpg 300w,/assets/resized/250/identityfirst.jpg 250w, /assets/img/identityfirst.jpg 643w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;progressive replace ui image medium floated right&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/resized/20/identityfirst.jpg&quot; class=&quot;preview ui image medium floated right&quot; alt=&quot;Identity first autism&quot; title=&quot;Identity first autism&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Which is it? Do you have autism or are you an autist? The choice is pretty clear to me; I am an autist. Autism is a part of who I am. It determines who I am as a person. There are more things that determine who I am as a person; I am a man, I am a Dutchman, I am a father, I am a realist and so on.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-the-problem-anyway&quot;&gt;What is the problem anyway?&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;These days it is “in” to be politically correct. We try to hit as few people as possible and, above all, we don’t want to hit people. We see plenty of examples of this in our society and world pasture. And then this kind of “discussion” comes up again. Is it now “wrong” to say that people with autism are autistic? Should we not do that because it puts the disease at the center? Because about people with another disease such as cancer, are we better to say that it is...
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://myautisticself.nl/2019/10/i-am-an-autist-vs-i-have-autism.html&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;>/a&gt;
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 13:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/10/i-am-an-autist-vs-i-have-autism.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/10/i-am-an-autist-vs-i-have-autism.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>persoonlijk</category></item><item>
        <title>Music vs. Silence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/music.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Muziek noten&quot; class=&quot;ui right floated image medium&quot; /&gt; When I’m busy with work or writing this blog, for example, I “need” to have music on. I know there are many people who prefer to work in silence, but for me that doesn’t actually work. I need music on to work concentrated.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1 id=&quot;music-on-concentration-on&quot;&gt;Music on, concentration on&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;By playing music, I can concentrate better. I listen to many different types of music when I work, but mostly the somewhat “louder” music. This can be, like now, Rammstein. But also hardcore, speedcore, terror, metal, folk, sometimes classical … It’s anything. I actually prefer hardcore, but I listen to all kinds of music.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I have music on, I can close myself off to the world around me. I can concentrate on my work or on writing a blog. If I don’t have music on, this is a lot harder for me. Writing a blog is easy and easy for me. However, I can get distracted quickly when I hear conversations around me, for example. However, if I can’t hear the conversations through the music, then logically they don’t distract me either.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1 id=&quot;sound-over-stimulation&quot;&gt;Sound over-stimulation?&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;I know that there are many...
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://myautisticself.nl/2019/10/music-vs-silence.html&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;>/a&gt;
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 12:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/10/music-vs-silence.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/10/music-vs-silence.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>muziek</category></item><item>
        <title>10 money questions for ...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/moneyeuros.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Website update&quot; class=&quot;ui right floated image medium&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Following the above post from &lt;a href=&quot;https://tistje.com&quot; title=&quot;Tistje - Ervaringsblog Autisme Sinds 2008&quot;&gt;Tistje&lt;/a&gt;, I thought it would be nice to fill this out for myself and share this with you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you spend a lot time think about money?&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe not as much as I should. Unfortunately, in our society (globally, not specifically in the Netherlands), money plays a very important role in everyone’s life. Without money, living in a western country is very difficult. But whether I’m personally doing a lot about it? No actually not. I am not very handy with money matters either. That is why I am in budget management.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is money a driver for you?&lt;/strong&gt; Partially. I won’t lie and say that money doesn’t hurt me. But it is not the primary motivator in my life. It is a means of survival and is therefore always good to have. Money alone does not make them happy, but it is always better to cry in a vila than in a box on the street.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you consider the financial consequences of changes in your life?&lt;/strong&gt; Yes. If it is a change in my life that...
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/10-money-questions-for.html&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;>/a&gt;
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 12:06:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/10-money-questions-for.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/10-money-questions-for.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>geld</category><category>persoonlijk</category></item><item>
        <title>Site update; no more Disqus</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/wall_e_pod_hires.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Website update&quot; class=&quot;ui right floated image large&quot; /&gt; Since I started this blog I have used a comment system called Disqus. This blog was not actually used by visitors to my blog. Not so strange actually, because most of the reactions I get outside of my blog. In particular via Twitter and Facebook. Commenting via the blog itself was never actually done.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is not bad at all, finally I also share my blogs via social media and I also respond to the feedback I receive there. However, it is true that my blog was delayed by the Disqus system. So today I decided to remove the comments. Instead I will use another system called “Webmentions”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1 id=&quot;webmentions-what-is-that&quot;&gt;Webmentions? What is that?&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;I myself am an computer person, but I will try to explain the concept here without too much technical fuss and difficult words. Webmentions is a technology where websites can respond to each other. This is a system that has been roaming the internet for some time. You may have heard about the concept of “Pingback”. Pingback is a way for a website (usually a blog) to let another website (also usually a blog) know that a...
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/site-update-no-more-diqus.html&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;>/a&gt;
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 12:44:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/site-update-no-more-diqus.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/site-update-no-more-diqus.html</guid><category>website</category><category>technisch</category></item><item>
        <title>Theory of Mind - Thinking Differently</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/thinking-tom.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;TOM - Thinking Differently&quot; class=&quot;ui image rounded floated right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Theory of mind, or &lt;abbr title=&quot;Theory of Mind&quot;&gt;TOM&lt;/abbr&gt;, is the science of human thinking. How people think and how they come to certain thoughts. &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/08/guide-asperger-syndrome-review.html&quot;&gt;In my review&lt;/a&gt; of Tony Attwood’s book I already mentioned this briefly. It is the theory about how people think and how connections are made within thoughts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are of course differences between the &lt;abbr title=&quot;Theory of Mind&quot;&gt;TOM&lt;/abbr&gt; of a neurotypic person and that of an autistic person. These differences cause misunderstandings between the two groups. Scientists also refer to these differences as “deficiencies in the theory of mind”. In my eyes this is a wrong statement. I prefer to call these “deficits” differences.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1 id=&quot;why-deficits-in-tom-is-harmful-to-autistic-self-esteem&quot;&gt;Why “deficits in &lt;abbr title=&quot;Theory of Mind&quot;&gt;TOM&lt;/abbr&gt;” is harmful to autistic self-esteem&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Calling the differences deficits affects the self-image of autists. It has a negative charge. I understand why this is called that, after all, it causes problems. These problems lie in not understanding people’s intentions and coming to other conclusions that deviate from the norm.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;By describing your &lt;abbr title=&quot;Theory of Mind&quot;&gt;TOM&lt;/abbr&gt; as “wrong” or “falling short”, you actually say that your way of thinking is inferior...
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/theory-of-mind-thinking-differently.html&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;>/a&gt;
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 13:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/theory-of-mind-thinking-differently.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/theory-of-mind-thinking-differently.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>tom</category><category>dit-is-autisme</category></item><item>
        <title>Being overstrung and hyposensitivity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/storming.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Storming&quot; class=&quot;ui floated right image rounded&quot; /&gt; Apparently I was overwhelmed the last few days. I felt “off”, not good in my skin and grumpy. Apparently that was the reason for some of my own behaviors and feelings that played out. It may be a bit strange to read, but I don’t really notice getting overstrung very well. What is the reason for this? Being sensitive to many things, including my own feelings and emotions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1 id=&quot;not-noticing-getting-overstrung&quot;&gt;Not noticing getting overstrung&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you read about overstimulation on the internet, you will always come across the same stories. People who, for example, have a headache due to sound or light. People soon notice that they are over-stimulated, usually within a few minutes to hours. I only notice this much later. And then I talk about days or sometimes even weeks later. And then I often have to be pointed out by others. I usually do not realize this myself. And why? Because I’m hyposensitive to stimuli. &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/06/ondergevoeligheid-en-autisme.html&quot;&gt;I previously wrote a blog post about this&lt;/a&gt;. Here I mainly describe my own experience with being hyposensitive. Because incentives and impressions come to me less than with most people, I also notice...
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/being-overstrung-and-hyposensitivity.html&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;>/a&gt;
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/being-overstrung-and-hyposensitivity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/being-overstrung-and-hyposensitivity.html</guid><category>overprikkeling</category><category>autisme</category><category>ondergevoeligheid</category><category>persoonlijk</category></item><item>
        <title>Stardate 73135.3 Social Anthropologist Log</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/alien-studing-earth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sociaal Antropoloog&quot; class=&quot;floated right ui image rounded&quot; /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;==== Start Log ====&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have often felt a stranger among these beings and today is no different. I have been inhabiting this planet for 35 years now and have learned. Learned how these beings interact with each other, what their motives are and what accepted behavior is. Today I write my logbook with the idea to help others like me understand what moves these beings and why they are the way they are.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;People are social tribal beings. They are similar to other herd animals that inhabit this planet. Remarkable behavior is shown in various situations and events. However, these do not seem to be the same between the different tribes. This is good to realize; the different tribes have different behaviors and will respond differently to each other.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My study of these beings began years ago when I was still growing. The different signals from these beings can sometimes be very confusing for us. They often seem to require eye contact when transferring information. It took a while before I recognized this behavior and therefore I was noticed. After I started to imitate this behavior, it became a...
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/stardate-73135-3-social-anthropologist-log.html&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;>/a&gt;
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 11:13:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/stardate-73135-3-social-anthropologist-log.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/09/stardate-73135-3-social-anthropologist-log.html</guid><category>autisme</category></item><item>
        <title>Honesty and other misconceptions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/wall-e.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Hello Friend!&quot; class=&quot;ui floated right image rounded&quot; /&gt; There are enough misconceptions about autism. There are quite a few prejudices and they sometimes make it difficult to deal with autism. People who are diagnosed at a somewhat later age (not if they are younger than ten or so) may already have prejudices and misconceptions about autism and what it means to be an autist. This of course has consequences; People become less open about their autism, sometimes feel embarrassed and other people sometimes treat you strangely when they know you have autism.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So it seemed like a good subject to talk about. There are enough prejudices, and I will miss some! So if you have additions yourself, or run into things that I don’t mention here, let me know!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1 id=&quot;autists-are-always-honest&quot;&gt;Autists are always honest&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is partly true. I know enough autists who are indeed always honest in most situations. It’s not really about lying. At least up to a certain height. I know of myself that I can tell a lie or keep things secret even when asked. However, it is true that I am direct. At least, according to NT people. This too is an expression...
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://myautisticself.nl/2019/08/honesty-and-other-misconceptions.html&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;>/a&gt;
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 09:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/08/honesty-and-other-misconceptions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/08/honesty-and-other-misconceptions.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>dit-is-autisme</category></item><item>
        <title>The Complete Guide To Asperger's Syndrome - Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/hulpgidsasperger.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hulpgids Asperger-syndroom&quot; class=&quot;ui image rounded&quot; /&gt; During my vacation I read the book “The Complete Guide To Asperger’s Syndrome” by Tony Attwood. And today I want to write a piece about this. Put first; this book was written when the DSM-IV was still current and the DSM-5 has since appeared. Tony Attwood has written a supplement for this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nieuwezijds.nl/boek/hulpgids-asperger-syndroom/special29/&quot;&gt;that can be downloaded from the publisher&lt;/a&gt;. I have also read this supplement and will include it in my review of this book.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I try to explain per chapter what the content is and what my view of the chapter was. This appears to be very extensive. That is why I have added a table of contents to this post. I hope you find it interesting! And now on to my review!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;aside id=&quot;aside-toc&quot; class=&quot;ui sidebar inverted vertical menu visible&quot;&gt; &lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#general-information&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-general-information&quot;&gt;General information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-reading-experience&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-reading-experience&quot;&gt;The Reading experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1---what-is-aspergers-syndrome&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-1---what-is-aspergers-syndrome&quot;&gt;Chapter 1 - What is Asperger’s syndrome?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2---the-diagnosis&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-2---the-diagnosis&quot;&gt;Chapter 2 - The Diagnosis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3---social-insight-and-friendships&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-3---social-insight-and-friendships&quot;&gt;Chapter 3 - Social insight and friendships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-4---teasing-and-bullying&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-4---teasing-and-bullying&quot;&gt;Chapter 4 - Teasing and bullying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5---theory-of-mind&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-5---theory-of-mind&quot;&gt;Chapter 5 - Theory of Mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-6---understanding-and-expressing-emotions&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-chapter-6---understanding-and-expressing-emotions&quot;&gt;Chapter 6 - Understanding and...
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://myautisticself.nl/2019/08/guide-asperger-syndrome-review.html&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;>/a&gt;
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 12:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/08/guide-asperger-syndrome-review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/08/guide-asperger-syndrome-review.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>review</category><category>asperger</category><category>tom</category></item><item>
        <title>Vacantion mode</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/is-my-autism-showing-5bboy5d-kids-premium-t-shirt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Is my autisme showing?&quot; class=&quot;post-image-right ui image rounded&quot; /&gt; It is summer vacation. The first two weeks of my vacation I have my children on the floor. Enjoying their presence. It also helps me to stay in my rhythm. Rhythm is important for me to remain stable, but it also provides clarity and structure for the children.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1 id=&quot;in-vacation-mode&quot;&gt;In vacation mode&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;But everything always turn out differently during the holidays. First, the children are with me for a longer time. “Normally” they are with me for a weekend. And now for two weeks. And two weeks is a while longer than usual. But I enjoy it to the full. Of course it requires the necessary adjustments on my side. My own structure is quite different from what the children are used to. But on the other hand it is a structure that I can adapt to quickly because of their presence.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When the children are there I try to stick to the meal times that I have received from home. So lunch at 12:00 and dinner at 6:00 pm. I also cook more than when I am alone. Of course you should cook every day, but I don’t...
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://myautisticself.nl/2019/08/vacantion-mode.html&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;>/a&gt;
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2019/08/vacantion-mode.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2019/08/vacantion-mode.html</guid><category>vakantie</category><category>2019</category><category>ritme</category></item></channel>
</rss>
