<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Autistic Self</title>
    <description>My blog about myself as an autist and my experiences with autism. Information and explanation for people without autism, a view of the world from someone with autism.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <link>https://myautisticself.nl/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://myautisticself.nl/feed_en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 10:48:11 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 10:48:11 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Video webinar online!]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[I gave a webinar on 26 August. This was recorded via Microsoft Teams and I put this recording online. You can watch this video here. 
So if you didn’t have the opportunity to watch it, or if you just want to see it again, you can do so here (or on YouTube).

Please note this webinar is in Dutch! No translation will be done for now. If you would like a English version, please message me through one of my social media.

&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;


        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/09/video-webinar-online_en.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 12:23:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/09/video-webinar-online_en.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/09/video-webinar-online_en.html</guid><category>webinar</category><category>autisme</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Webinar - The journey to my diagnosis]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[
On the 26th of August at 20:00 in the evening I will give a webinar about my journey to the diagnosis of autism. It will be my personal story in which I will discuss the challenges of the past, the road I have travelled and where I am now.

During the webinar there will also be room to ask questions. I hope to see you at my first public webinar on August 26th! Be advised that the webinar will be in Dutch! There will be no translation available at the time, sorry. Maybe in the future I will do an English one.

This webinar is made possible by the Autisme Netwerk Friesland

Details

26 August 20.00-21.30h (login from 19.50h)
Completely free of charge.

You can participate via this link: Participate in Microsoft Teams meeting
How does Teams work? Check the website: http://www.autismenetwerkfriesland.nl/nieuws


    Add to Calendar
    2020-08-26 20:00
    2020-08-26 21:30
    Europe/Amsterdam
    Webinar - The journey to my diagnosis
    Webinar by David Westerink, made possible by the Autisme Netwerk Friesland. About his journey to the diagnosis of autism
    https://bit.ly/349VsQn
    15



        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/08/webinar-the-journey-to-my-diagnosis.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 12:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/08/webinar-the-journey-to-my-diagnosis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/08/webinar-the-journey-to-my-diagnosis.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>webinar</category><category>voorlichting</category><category>begrip</category><category>acceptatie</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Dealing with ableism]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Society has a problem. A problem with anomalies. As soon as you deviate from what society sees as the norm, you are closed out. This does not always happen consciously, or with wrong intentions. Yet it causes problems for people. The world of man is made by the majority, or at least by the people who have appropriated power. Minorities, the deviations, have (as the name implies) less to contribute. Ableism Sometimes people talk about ableism, but what does it actually mean? Ableism (/ˈeɪbəlɪzəm/; also known as ablism, disablism (Brit. English), anapirophobia, anapirism, and disability discrimination) is discrimination and social prejudice against people with disabilities or who are perceived to have disabilities. Ableism characterizes persons as defined by their disabilities and as inferior to the non-disabled. On this basis, people are assigned or denied certain perceived abilities, skills, or character orientations. Wikipedia - Ableism Ableism has a strong presence within the society in which we live. The idea that people who deviate in a certain way are automatically less. It has to with the prejudices that people have. As soon as someone is told that a person they know has an anomaly, they automatically make assumptions about made the anomaly....

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/07/dealing-with-ableism.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 12:44:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/07/dealing-with-ableism.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/07/dealing-with-ableism.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>validisme</category><category>acceptatie</category><category>begrip</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Webinar Vera Helleman - A review]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Last week, 17 June 2020, Vera Helleman gave a webinar entitled “The Power of Autism”, about what she called “the three pillars of autism”. Together with about 650 other people I watched this webinar. Today I will write down my thoughts about it on paper. The webinar itself can be seen on the website of Vera Helleman herself until 24 June 2020. Let me start by saying that Vera and I are very different people. We look at the world in a very different way, yet there are many similarities in our view of autism. The webinar started very well on time, after all, a date is a date. Without much ado she started her lecture in which she explains her points. I noticed that the chat went well (it was already available before the lecture started) and a lot of people were present. At some moments audio and video were not synchronous, the video seemed to stand still or the audio dropped out. From the chat I saw that this problem occurred to more people. I myself didn’t find this very disturbing (I watch a lot of live broadcasts on the internet and it happens more often), but some...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/06/webinar-vera-helleman-a-review.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 10:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/06/webinar-vera-helleman-a-review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/06/webinar-vera-helleman-a-review.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>review</category><category>acceptatie</category><category>dit-is-autisme</category><category>neurodiversiteit</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Talk about autism]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Before I was diagnosed with “Asperger’s Syndrome” at the age of 30, I didn’t really know anything about autism. It was something I had never looked at. It was outside my area of interest. It’s different nowadays, I can even call it my special interest. All my life before I was diagnosed I knew I was “different” from the people around me. I felt like an extraterrestrial being who had to adapt to the people living here in the world. This also aroused my interest in studying people. It has always intrigued me what people do “tap”, why they do as they do. This is actually out of self interest; if I knew why people do as they do, I could do the same. So without knowing I was busy masking, adapting to neurotypical people in order not to fall out of tune. Today I can do the latter much less. I still adapt, but I don’t hide my own self behind a mask of neurotypical behaviour anymore. I embrace my autism as it is, a profound part of who I am. Partly because of this I dare to write very openly and talk about my autism. About what kind...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/06/talk-about-autism.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 13:51:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/06/talk-about-autism.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/06/talk-about-autism.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>acceptatie</category><category>begrip</category><category>neurodiversiteit</category><category>voorlichting</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[The art of procrastination ...]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[There are plenty of times for me to think that I didn’t want to do something in my life. Things I’ve dodged, decisions I haven’t made, or even put off problems for so long that they’ve solved themselves. There have been many more times when I honestly forgot things. Since my diagnosis, I have looked at myself and others a lot. Self-study, but in a literal sense of the word. I often compare behaviour. Not only from myself to others, or from others to me, but certainly also difference in behavior of myself. How can you learn to deal with yourself when I don’t know what you’re doing. I’ve known about my procrastination behaviour for a long time, it’s not new to me. Is it a beautiful side? Certainly not, there’s going to be enough trouble saying it’s a harmful trait… From procrastination… If I’m good at something, it’s procrastination. How many times I keep telling myself “I’ll do it tomorrow” or excuses like that, I’ve noticed a source. If I’m doing well, I’ll deal with things right away. No delay, unless it is necessary of course, but otherwise I prefer to do things as soon as possible. Then it’s...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/06/the-art-of-procrastination.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 12:06:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/06/the-art-of-procrastination.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/06/the-art-of-procrastination.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>sociaal-gedrag</category><category>stress</category><category>spanning</category><category>ritme</category><category>werk</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Beautiful sides of my autism]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Today I was asked the question: “What do you think are the beautiful aspects of your autism?” I think this is a very nice question! Especially because a lot of people don’t think about their positive and beautiful sides. It’s a question that made me think about myself and look at myself in a good way. Maybe it’s a question we should ask ourselves more often. Not specifically as an autistic person, but as a human being. What are your good sides? But in this case it’s specifically about my autism. Not autism in general, because I certainly can’t speak for all autistic people. But for myself I can answer this question. Self-knowledge To see the beautiful sides of yourself, you need a dose of self-knowledge. Insight into who you are, what you do and how your thought world works. The past few years I have been busy getting to know myself and exploring myself. A kind of soul searching you could say. However, for me this was not a spiritual experience, but rather a rational determination of norms, values and boundaries. Different than usual A beautiful side of my autism is that I’m different from other people. Of course...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/05/beautiful-sides-of-my-autism.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 13:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/05/beautiful-sides-of-my-autism.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/05/beautiful-sides-of-my-autism.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>dit-is-autisme</category><category>positief</category><category>persoonlijk</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Anxiety, stress, tension and autism]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[I had an interview with Autism in Context about fear, stress, tension and autism. This interview was posted on their YouTube channel “Fear and Autism”. On this channel you can find several interviews with autistic people who talk about their experiences with stress and tension.

In this interview I discuss my ways of dealing with stress, fear and tension. Below you can watch the interview. This interview is in Dutch, just a heads up :wink:

&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;


        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/05/anxiety-stress-tension-and-autism.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 12:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/05/anxiety-stress-tension-and-autism.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/05/anxiety-stress-tension-and-autism.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>stress</category><category>spanning</category><category>angst</category><category>dit-is-autisme</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Self diagnosis in the Netherlands]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Diagnosing your own autism when you have no education or experience to do so, is that anything you can do at all? Opinions run out of one. Here in the Netherlands where I live, we have (generally) good health care. We have fairly easy access to a general practitioner, hospitals and mental health care. At least, if I compare this with, for example, America where this is absolutely not the case. I think the notion of ascribing the autism diagnosis to yourself comes from there as well. From countries like America, where it is not so easy to get a diagnosis. Either because the doctors don’t want to make the diagnosis (as unfortunately still happens with women), or because the costs for visiting a doctor are too high (they don’t have a basic health insurance as we have here). But that is there. I want to write more about diagnosing your autism here in the Netherlands. Is it a thing to do? Is it necessary? Self-diagnosis versus an official diagnosis Is it possible to diagnose autism yourself? In my opinion this is partly yes and partly no. Look, you can recognize yourself in, for example, a symptom list of ASD,...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/self-diagnosis-in-the-netherlands.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 13:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/self-diagnosis-in-the-netherlands.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/self-diagnosis-in-the-netherlands.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>diagnose</category><category>acceptatie</category><category>begrip</category><category>asperger</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Acceptance of Autism - The How and Why]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[For some people, accepting the fact that they are autistic is quite a challenge. When I was diagnosed, I was also told that I would go through a grieving process. The feeling of losing the “normal” things. When I was told this, I shrugged my shoulders and thought it would be okay. In my case there was also the fact that I was in the middle of a severe depression, much lower than that I couldn’t sink in my eyes. I did have this mourning process. I noticed to myself that I had thoughts like “If only I had known then” and “Suppose the people around me had known about me”. This with varying feelings. Somehow I was glad that the people around me didn’t know, bullies in my past had enough to make me look ridiculous. But in other cases perhaps problems could have been avoided. Improductive thinking All these thoughts got in my way. That line of thought didn’t make me any better. I tried to keep an eye on myself and catch myself on, what I called, “imagine that thinking”. As soon as a thought of mine started with “Suppose so”, “What if”, “If only” or “If...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/acceptance-of-autism-the-how-and-why.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 13:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/acceptance-of-autism-the-how-and-why.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/acceptance-of-autism-the-how-and-why.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>acceptatie</category><category>filosofie</category><category>gaut</category><category>gedachtes</category><category>sociaal-gedrag</category></item></channel>
</rss>
