<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Autistic Self</title>
    <description>My blog about myself as an autist and my experiences with autism. Information and explanation for people without autism, a view of the world from someone with autism.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <link>https://myautisticself.nl/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://myautisticself.nl/feed_en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 13:22:36 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 13:22:36 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Self diagnosis in the Netherlands]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Diagnosing your own autism when you have no education or experience to do so, is that anything you can do at all? Opinions run out of one. Here in the Netherlands where I live, we have (generally) good health care. We have fairly easy access to a general practitioner, hospitals and mental health care. At least, if I compare this with, for example, America where this is absolutely not the case. I think the notion of ascribing the autism diagnosis to yourself comes from there as well. From countries like America, where it is not so easy to get a diagnosis. Either because the doctors don’t want to make the diagnosis (as unfortunately still happens with women), or because the costs for visiting a doctor are too high (they don’t have a basic health insurance as we have here). But that is there. I want to write more about diagnosing your autism here in the Netherlands. Is it a thing to do? Is it necessary? Self-diagnosis versus an official diagnosis Is it possible to diagnose autism yourself? In my opinion this is partly yes and partly no. Look, you can recognize yourself in, for example, a symptom list of ASD,...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/self-diagnosis-in-the-netherlands.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 13:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/self-diagnosis-in-the-netherlands.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/self-diagnosis-in-the-netherlands.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>diagnose</category><category>acceptatie</category><category>begrip</category><category>asperger</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Acceptance of Autism - The How and Why]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[For some people, accepting the fact that they are autistic is quite a challenge. When I was diagnosed, I was also told that I would go through a grieving process. The feeling of losing the “normal” things. When I was told this, I shrugged my shoulders and thought it would be okay. In my case there was also the fact that I was in the middle of a severe depression, much lower than that I couldn’t sink in my eyes. I did have this mourning process. I noticed to myself that I had thoughts like “If only I had known then” and “Suppose the people around me had known about me”. This with varying feelings. Somehow I was glad that the people around me didn’t know, bullies in my past had enough to make me look ridiculous. But in other cases perhaps problems could have been avoided. Improductive thinking All these thoughts got in my way. That line of thought didn’t make me any better. I tried to keep an eye on myself and catch myself on, what I called, “imagine that thinking”. As soon as a thought of mine started with “Suppose so”, “What if”, “If only” or “If...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/acceptance-of-autism-the-how-and-why.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 13:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/acceptance-of-autism-the-how-and-why.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/acceptance-of-autism-the-how-and-why.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>acceptatie</category><category>filosofie</category><category>gaut</category><category>gedachtes</category><category>sociaal-gedrag</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[How do you think positively? | Stay happy]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Following feedback on my previous blog post I am writing this post today. Thinking positive is not the easiest as I already wrote. However, there are a few tricks and tips I can give to stay positive, even if it’s all wrong. How do you stay positive when things don’t go the way you want them to? Life often turns out differently than you planned. This happens to all of us and can be very annoying at times. Plans are broken and appointments don’t go through. Especially in this day and age with all the measures around COVID-19. Especially if you have a great need for clarity and structure, it can be difficult to keep thinking positively. In my opinion, it is very important to continue to look realistically at the situation in which you find yourself. This isn’t easy for everyone to do, but I’m someone who has more to do with logical thinking than with emotional thinking. That also makes it sometimes difficult for me to deal with emotions, but I am finding my way through this better and better. I myself have a kind of step-by-step plan that I follow to deal with things that don’t work...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/how-do-you-think-positive-stay-happy.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 14:01:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/how-do-you-think-positive-stay-happy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/how-do-you-think-positive-stay-happy.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>positief</category><category>sociaal-gedrag</category><category>gedachtes</category><category>crisis</category><category>dit-is-autisme</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[The power of positivity | Stay happy]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[It’s a wonderful thing, the human brain. We are able to form thoughts about all kinds of things and yet there are things that don’t always go well. It is sometimes difficult to deal with and works in a different way for everyone. Yet there are things that work the same way for most people. Research has been going on for years about how the brain works and why it works this way. Today I want to talk about the power of positive thinking and doing. In this time of many changes in our daily lives and the worries that this brings to most of us, it is sometimes difficult to stay positive. In addition, the human brain has evolved to remember negative experiences better than positive experiences. Negative thinking is part of survival To understand why we have negative experiences, we have to go far back. Back to a time when we had to fight to survive. Hunting for food and looking for shelter every day. Thousands of years ago, we had already learned that it was better for us to stay together in groups. We could take care of each other, power in numbers. If we went after...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/the-strength-of-positivity-stay-happy.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 12:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/the-strength-of-positivity-stay-happy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/the-strength-of-positivity-stay-happy.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>positief</category><category>sociaal-gedrag</category><category>gedachtes</category><category>crisis</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[The AutCast podcast has started!]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Today, on world autism day 2020, it is time! My first episode of the AutCast has come online. As part of the autism week I had the idea to launch the podcast. And today seemed like the perfect moment. This first episode is meant as an introduction and is quite short (less than 10 minutes), but in the future I hope to make some deeper (and longer) episodes. Mind you the podcast is in Dutch! No English version is planned for now, but maybe if people want it, I can see what I can do. If you would like a English version, please contact me! Very good at starting It’s been a while since I for the first time on this blog talked about podcasts and my intention to start 1 myself. Often in the past it has turned out that I’m quite good at starting things. Finishing is often another story. But I’ve proven to myself by writing this blog that I can** do it. For me the trick is that I should like to do it. And writing and talking about neurodiversity is what I like to do. So it was a logical choice for me to see...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/the-autcast-podcast-has-started.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 13:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/the-autcast-podcast-has-started.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/04/the-autcast-podcast-has-started.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>podcasts</category><category>OurGoldenMoment</category><category>Gaut</category><category>AutismeWeek2020</category><category>neurodiversiteit</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Online week of #Gaut]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[It’s so far! Autism Week 2020 has been going on for a few days now. Unfortunately it is a bit a different week than normal for autism week. Where normally actions are organized throughout the country and people come together to talk about autism in all its facets, we are now forced to stay at home. For most autistic people this is not the problem, sitting at home and dealing with people very little. What is a problem for most autistic people is to break the normal structure. This is a problem in itself and I don’t want to go into too much detail now, but it does lead to the activities we see online. People who have been looking forward to their part in autism week want to continue that now anyway. So we don’t cancel anything, we just move it! The Week of #Gaut And that’s why we’re moving the actions to 100% online! And we are doing our best to pay as much attention online as possible to this week of #Gaut. Now you’ve seen the #Gaut hashtag pass by a number of times. This hashtag follows the international hashtag #OurGoldenMoment and refers to the color gold...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/03/online-week-of-gaut.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 11:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/03/online-week-of-gaut.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/03/online-week-of-gaut.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>autismeweek2020</category><category>gaut</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Lifeline]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Weird word actually, lifeline. Yesterday I was in bed and very restless. Restless because of everything that’s going on in the country. The worries about people in my family who are among the “weakest” in the Netherlands. The past few days it has also been very difficult to hold on to my structure, my life rhythm turned back to living at night and sleeping during the day. Last night I was restless as I wrote, I noticed it in my body. I also noticed it because I didn’t answer several chat messages and other notifications from the social media. Remotely I noticed that I pulled back and was in my head. It may not be easy for others to understand what this feels like, but I will do my best to describe it. I’ll get back to the lifeline :wink: When I’m in the state I was in last night, I feel like I’m looking at myself from different angles. I’m restless and my thoughts are spinning through my head, through each other and over each other. And then there comes a moment when somewhere in my head there is some kind of distance. As if I take a step...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/03/lifeline.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 11:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/03/lifeline.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/03/lifeline.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>crisis</category><category>gedachtes</category><category>fantasie</category><category>begrip</category><category>ritme</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[The color of autism is gold]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[We’re in March. Next month is autism month and in the Netherlands autism week. Different things are organized for this. Many organizations try to bring autism to the attention of the public. Part of this are the different symbols and colors that are used. Many see the well-known puzzle pieces and the color blue as the color that stands for autism. Why is the colour of autism gold? The chemical symbol for gold is Au. This symbol has been picked up by the neurodiversity movement on the internet and baptized to the “Autistic Union”. Abbreviated to Âû. With this also the color gold was adopted as the basic color for autism. People on Twitter and other social media started including the letters Âû in their name to let others know that they are part of this union. With this they try to indicate that they are open to talk about autism and are willing to answer questions that people have. What’s wrong with blue? I wrote earlier about the problem with blue, but I’ll summarize it. The color blue was invented by an organization called “Autism Speaks” from America. One of the goals of this organization is to find a...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/03/the-color-of-autism-is-gold.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 11:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/03/the-color-of-autism-is-gold.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/03/the-color-of-autism-is-gold.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>OurGoldenMoment</category><category>RedInstead</category><category>neurodiversiteit</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[The role of spokesperson]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Most people today have heard the word autism. Many people only know autism from TV or from the news. Or maybe used as a horror image by people who promote pseudoscience. Gradually people also know autism from their own environment; colleagues, friends or family who have been diagnosed. Still, there is not much familiarity among people about what autism is or what influence it has on people diagnosed with it. That is why providing information about autism is important to do. Fortunately, there are organisations in the Netherlands that deal with this. For example the NVA and the various autism networks in the Netherlands such as the Autisme Netwerk Friesland. My role as spokesman Since I started blogging last summer I notice that people often recognize my stories and appreciate what I’m doing here. Partly for this reason I have decided to take this to the next level; I want to take the role of spokesperson seriously. That’s why I recently joined the Autisme Netwerk Friesland and started to expand my network. I have also made it known that I am available to, for example, give a lecture about autism at an organisation. Now it so happens that within my...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/03/the-role-of-spokesperson.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 12:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/03/the-role-of-spokesperson.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/03/the-role-of-spokesperson.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>begrip</category><category>neurodiversiteit</category><category>lezingen</category><category>voorlichting</category></item><item>
        <title><![CDATA[Time is a strange thing]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[. Time is a concept we don’t think much about. Time is a way of measuring how long something has been or how long it will last. As we now know, time is also relative. That means that time is not always experienced in the same way. A famous example is that of a stove; 5 seconds with your hand on a hot stove is very long, but 5 minutes to be with your loved one is too short. Time also differs when it comes to experience between people. I notice this almost every day. Of course this has to do with many different factors, such as culture, upbringing and patience. Still, I notice that my awareness of time differs from the neurotypical people around me. I find it very difficult to remember how long ago a certain incident was. I have to remember this with hints, such as documents that are dated and have a relationship with the incident. Or with help from people who were there. Otherwise it soon becomes a case of “about 5-7 years ago, I believe”. And whether that’s true then, depends on it. Time and the value of social relationships I have noticed that...

        Read more: https://myautisticself.nl/2020/02/time-is-a-strange-thing.html
        ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 12:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://myautisticself.nl/2020/02/time-is-a-strange-thing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://myautisticself.nl/2020/02/time-is-a-strange-thing.html</guid><category>autisme</category><category>ondergevoeligheid</category><category>dit-is-autisme</category></item></channel>
</rss>
